http://www.dfci.harvard.edu/privacy-policy/

Read disclaimer about translations
Please note that some translations using Google Translate may not be accurately represented and downloaded documents cannot be translated. Dana-Farber assumes no liability for inaccuracies that may result from using this third-party tool, which is for website translation and not clinical interactions. You may request a live medical interpreter for a discussion about your care.
Privacy Policy
Home
Privacy Policy
Share
Print
Email
Dana-Farber Website Privacy Policy
At Dana-Farber, your privacy is important to us and we take important steps to protect the privacy and security of your information.
This Privacy Policy will tell you what information, including personal information, we may collect from you via Dana-Farber.org and other Dana-Farber operated websites (the "Website"), how it is used, how it is shared, and what your choices are. By providing
personal information to us, you consent to our collection, use and sharing of your personal information in accordance with this Privacy Policy.
We may occasionally make changes to our Privacy Policy. Whenever a change is made to our Privacy Policy, we will update the information on this page so please review this Privacy Policy regularly. This policy does not govern how we use your protected
health information ("PHI"), as defined under the Health Insurance Portability & Accountability Act and related regulations. That information is governed by Dana-Farber's Notice of Privacy Practices. If you have any questions about Dana-Farber's Notice of Privacy Practices, please contact us at privacy@dfci.harvard.edu.
All references to 'us,' 'we' or 'our' in this Privacy Policy are references to Dana-Farber. All references to 'you,' 'your' or 'user' in this Privacy Policy are references to any individual who accesses or uses this Website.
Confidentiality
An individual may use our Website without disclosing personal information. However, when you submit a request or communication on our Website, we may need to collect personal information about you. For example, you may be asked to provide your name, email
address, or demographic information if you choose to complete any online forms used for class registration, special events and promotions or appointment requests, or to provide feedback about this Website.
Security
Dana-Farber takes precautions to protect our users' personal information. For example, we maintain a secure firewall and use all reasonable efforts to prevent unauthorized access to personal information collected through our Website. We also maintain
an information security infrastructure that protects the integrity and privacy of such personal information. Your personal information is also encrypted during transmission. Encryption is a common method used to transmit sensitive data across the
Internet. Encryption temporarily makes the text unreadable during the time it is being transmitted over the Internet.
Cookies, Tracking, and Interest-Based Advertising
The Dana-Farber Website works with third-party products or services ("Service Providers") (including Google, Facebook, and other Service Providers) who help us track and analyze visitor activity on the Website, measure the effectiveness of our advertising
efforts, and support the optimization of our digital marketing campaigns.
The Dana-Farber Website uses "cookies," tracking pixels and related technologies. These can be set by Dana-Farber or by our Service Providers. Cookies are small data files that online services can store on, and retrieve from, a user's computer or mobile
device through the web browser. The information is stored and retrievable either for the duration of a website visit (known as "session cookies"), or until some later point in time set by the website dropping the cookie (known as "persistent cookies").
Examples of information we and our Service Providers collect include how often someone visits our Website and what they do while on our Website. We and our Service Providers use this information in the aggregate to understand how our visitors as a group
use different resources and to help us improve our Website. We and our Service Providers also collect information about the activity of individual website users. Further, our Service Providers may match that information with additional information
for our benefit, including from third party sources. This information may be used to direct related Dana-Farber advertisements and/or informational content to website users on other websites.
Most internet browsers accept cookies by default, but you can modify your browser preferences to block or restrict cookies if you do not want your web browsing activity tracked. You can access the information on the Dana-Farber Website without enabling
cookies in your browser, but disabling cookies may result in a diminished ability to take advantage of the services and related informational content on the Website. There are a variety of publicly available third-party tools that manage cookies and
similar technologies that collect information related to your use of the Website. Learn more from the FTC or adjust your tracking preferences. Of course, we are not responsible for the effectiveness or compliance standards of these third-party tools and opt-out mechanisms. Please note that if you delete your cookies or upgrade your browser
after blocking cookies or opting out, you will need to block or delete cookies and opt-out again if you visit our Website again. Further, if you use multiple browsers or devices to access the Dana-Farber Website, you will need to block or delete cookies
and opt-out on each browser or device.
Dana-Farber deploys the Facebook Pixel on this Website. The Facebook Pixel may enable Facebook to match website visitors with their Facebook User Accounts. You can find out more about how Facebook uses data when you visit our Website by visiting Facebook's
Data Policy page, "What kinds of information do we collect? > Information from partners."
We may use web analytics and tag management services and tools service provided by Google and other third parties to collect certain information relating to your use of the Website. You can find out more about how Google uses data when you visit our Website
by visiting Google's Privacy Policy, "How Google uses data when you use our partners' sites or apps."
Our Service Providers may acquire additional information about your activity on our Website, including pages you visit, access times, visit duration, how you arrived at our Website and your IP address. An IP address is a number that identifies a device
connected to the Internet. For most devices, the IP address changes on at least a weekly basis.
Our Service Providers may also acquire device identifiers and specific information about the browser you use. In some cases, this information may be unique to you.
Donor Information Collection and Use
Dana-Farber does not sell or rent donor information to others, but we do occasionally exchange donor mailing lists with other non-profit organizations for fundraising purposes. This process helps us engage new supporters, saves us money and is carefully
monitored. One may always opt out by contacting the Annual Giving office at 617-632-6099 or annual_giving@dfci.harvard.edu.
Giving to Dana-Farber and the Jimmy Fund
When you make a gift on our Website, with a check or other physical form of payment, your email address and mailing address will be entered into our donor database. We may send you emails or mailings in the future informing you of other giving opportunities
or providing news about Dana-Farber or the Jimmy Fund.
If you choose not to receive any further communication from us, you may opt-out as follows:
Opt Out of Mailings
If you wish to opt out of receiving fundraising mail from Dana-Farber and the Jimmy Fund, please call 800-525-4669 or visit this print opt out form.
Opt Out of Email
If you wish to opt out of receiving fundraising emails from Dana-Farber and the Jimmy Fund, please call 800-525-4669 or visit this email opt out form.
You may also contact the following Office of Philanthropy Departments for questions about fundraising communications:
Online Donations/Mail Appeals
Phone: 617-632-6099 Email: annual_giving@dfci.harvard.edu
Boston Marathon® Jimmy Fund Walk
Phone: 866-JFW-HERO or 866-539-4376 Email: jimmyfundwalk@dfci.harvard.edu
Running Programs
Phone: 617-632-1970 Email: dfmc@dfci.harvard.edu
Jimmy Fund Golf
Phone: 866-521-4653 Email: jimmyfund_golf@dfci.harvard.edu
Event Fundraising
Phone: 800-52-JIMMY or 800-525-4669 Email: jimmyfundevents@dfci.harvard.edu
Opt Out of Dana-Farber E-Newsletters
If you currently receive an E-Newsletter and would like to unsubscribe, you may do so in two ways. In an E-News email, scroll to the bottom of the message to where it guides you to "manage your preferences." Click on the "opt out" link in that section
to remove yourself from the E-News email list. If you do not have a copy of the E-News, send us an unsubscribe request at JimmyFundContactUs@dfci.harvard.edu with "Opt out of E-Newsletter"
as your subject. Be sure to include your name and email address.
Users in the European Economic Area ("EEA") and Switzerland
If you are a resident of EEA or Switzerland, you are entitled to the rights under Chapter III of the EU General Data Protection Regulation ("GDPR") or Section 2 of the Swiss Federal Act on Data Protection with respect to the processing of your personal
data, that is within the scope of the GDPR, in connection with your use of this Website.
As a supplement to the information provided above, we would like to inform you:
In addition to collecting personal information directly from you, we may also collect or receive information about you from other sources including public databases, business partners or other third parties.
We will keep your personal information for as long as is necessary for the purposes set out in this Privacy Policy, subject to your right, under certain circumstances, to have certain of your personal information erased, as discussed below, unless
a longer period is required under applicable law or is needed to resolve disputes or protect our legal rights. Once this time period has expired, we will delete your data.
We would like to make sure you are fully aware of all of your data protection rights. Every user from the EEA and/or Switzerland is entitled to the following:
The right to access — You have the right to request copies of your personal data. We may charge you a small fee for this service.
The right to rectification — You have the right to request that we correct any information you believe is inaccurate. You also have the right to request that we complete the information you believe is incomplete.
The right to erasure — You have the right to request that we erase your personal data, under certain conditions.
The right to restrict processing — You have the right to request that we restrict the processing of your personal data, under certain conditions.
The right to object to processing — You have the right to object to our processing of your personal data, under certain conditions.
The right to data portability — You have the right to request that we transfer the data that we have collected to another organization, or directly to you, under certain conditions.
If you would like to exercise any of these rights, please:
Contact us by email at privacy@dfci.harvard.edu
Call us at 617-632-6593
In order to verify your identity, we may require you to provide us with personal information prior to accessing any records containing information about you.
If you make a request to exercise any of these rights, we have one month to respond to you.
Last Updated
December 18, 2019
